<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Alvin Sim</title>
    <link>http://localhost/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Alvin Sim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 15:51:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Which &#39;yarn&#39;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/which-yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 15:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/which-yarn/</guid>
      <description>This has happened to me each time I setup a new Debian or Ubuntu environment. Firstly, the yarn command I am referring to here is the JavaScript &amp;ldquo;Yarn&amp;rdquo; package manager. The yarn that was installed or already installed was the one used by the cmdtest.
I thought I had yarn installed when I checked using the command which yarn and out printed /usr/bin/yarn.
$ which yarn /usr/bin/yarn When I ran yarn upgrade I got this weird error message:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;git status&#39; in Your Prompt</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/git-status-in-your-prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 12:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/git-status-in-your-prompt/</guid>
      <description>Did you know: You can have a visual representation of the git status command output in your shell prompt? This is especially convenient for people who use the git command-line interface (CLI). Unfortunately, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with the Windows command prompt or cmd. But there are a few workarounds.
git-prompt.sh Disclaimer: For this part of the article, I will show the how-tos by using Debian (on Windows Subsystem for Linux or WSL) and FreeBSD as examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/my-experience-with-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 13:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/my-experience-with-wsl/</guid>
      <description>One day on my way back home, I was listening to one of Hanselminutes&amp;rsquo;s podcast episodes titled &amp;ldquo;Inside Linux on Windows with WSL and Tara Raj&amp;rdquo;.
This reminded me of the first time I tried it when Microsoft first announced it back in 2016. Then, it was called &amp;ldquo;Bash on Windows&amp;rdquo; and Microsoft collaborated with Canonical, the company behind Ubuntu.
Personally, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use it much. It was just another shiny new toy and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a use for it then.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
