<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Alvin Sim</title>
    <link>http://localhost/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alvin Sim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 11:16:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SSH Keys Suddenly Refused to Connect</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/ssh-keys-suddenly-refused-to-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 11:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/ssh-keys-suddenly-refused-to-connect/</guid>
      <description>Strangely, my Debian system (running on WSL) suddenly refused to connect to both Gitlab and GitHub using my SSH keys. Everything was fine when I last used it a couple of weeks ago. But now running the command ssh -Tv git@github.com returns a &amp;ldquo;Connection timed out&amp;rdquo; error.
And I didn&amp;rsquo;t see the same issue using the same SSH keys on a Ubuntu system (also running on WSL) and Git Bash on Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which &#39;yarn&#39;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/which-yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 15:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/which-yarn/</guid>
      <description>This has happened to me each time I setup a new Debian or Ubuntu environment. Firstly, the yarn command I am referring to here is the JavaScript &amp;ldquo;Yarn&amp;rdquo; package manager. The yarn that was installed or already installed was the one used by the cmdtest.
I thought I had yarn installed when I checked using the command which yarn and out printed /usr/bin/yarn.
$ which yarn /usr/bin/yarn When I ran yarn upgrade I got this weird error message:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Chocolatey Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/its-a-chocolatey-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 13:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/its-a-chocolatey-time/</guid>
      <description>Chocolatey is a software or package management on Windows, similar to the apt command on Debian or Debian-based distributions. It&amp;rsquo;d be great if Windows has something similar built-in. This does make managing software so much easier.
I have used Chocolatey for many years, since 2016 or earlier, and it is always one of the first things I install on a new Windows system.
One of the main advantages of using Chocolatey and because it is a command-line-interface (CLI) power tool, is installations and upgrading of software can be automated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Podcast Shows I Enjoy Listening To</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/2019-podcast-shows-i-enjoy-listening-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 12:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/2019-podcast-shows-i-enjoy-listening-to/</guid>
      <description>I listen to podcasts because it is one of the ways I can learn something new. There was a quote from someone, from whom I can&amp;rsquo;t remember, &amp;ldquo;Podcast is like a moving university&amp;rdquo;. I will always have something to listen to when I am doing my chores, commute, having my walks or exercise, etc.
Below is a list of the podcast shows I enjoy listening to currently and they are ordered in no particular order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Web Experience with the Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/a-better-web-experience-with-the-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 11:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/a-better-web-experience-with-the-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>When I use a computer, I like to have both hands on the keyboard, or specifically on the home row. I find that it is more productive than having to move them to grab the mouse every few seconds. This is one reason I am grateful for
Software with great keyboard shortcuts and also that are easily customisable. Terminal (or terminal emulator) and command prompt which you do not really need to use the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;git status&#39; in Your Prompt</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/git-status-in-your-prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 12:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/git-status-in-your-prompt/</guid>
      <description>Did you know: You can have a visual representation of the git status command output in your shell prompt? This is especially convenient for people who use the git command-line interface (CLI). Unfortunately, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with the Windows command prompt or cmd. But there are a few workarounds.
git-prompt.sh Disclaimer: For this part of the article, I will show the how-tos by using Debian (on Windows Subsystem for Linux or WSL) and FreeBSD as examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Not DuckDuckGo?</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/why-not-duckduckgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 02:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/why-not-duckduckgo/</guid>
      <description>DuckDuckGo is a privacy-first search engine which doesn&amp;rsquo;t track you. I started using it as my primary search engine in 2011. Below is my first tweet about DuckDuckGo. In the tweet, I shared an article on an interview (2012) by TechSpot with DuckDuckGo&amp;rsquo;s founder, Gabriel Weinberg.
I&amp;rsquo;ve used duckduckgo for more than a year &amp;amp; it&amp;rsquo;s AWESOME. It is currently the default search engine in all my browsers http://t.co/Dngw2s9d</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/my-experience-with-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 13:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/my-experience-with-wsl/</guid>
      <description>One day on my way back home, I was listening to one of Hanselminutes&amp;rsquo;s podcast episodes titled &amp;ldquo;Inside Linux on Windows with WSL and Tara Raj&amp;rdquo;.
This reminded me of the first time I tried it when Microsoft first announced it back in 2016. Then, it was called &amp;ldquo;Bash on Windows&amp;rdquo; and Microsoft collaborated with Canonical, the company behind Ubuntu.
Personally, I didn&amp;rsquo;t use it much. It was just another shiny new toy and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a use for it then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A War With My Laptop&#39;s Touchpad</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/a-war-with-my-laptops-touchpad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 03:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/a-war-with-my-laptops-touchpad/</guid>
      <description>I use a 15&amp;quot; HP Pavillion and the touchpad drives me crazy. This happens with Dells&amp;rsquo; as well. The one thing about the touchpad that bugs me, is when I start typing and ghostly things would start to happen such as my web browser will be the active window and new tabs and/or windows will start opening; or the right-click context menu would appear. Changing the sensitivity of the touchpad didn&amp;rsquo;t help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refresh Environment Variables in Windows Command Prompt</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/refresh-env-vars-in-windows-cmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 12:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/refresh-env-vars-in-windows-cmd/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever added an environment variable in Windows and having to close and re-open the command prompt just to use it? Or worse, having to reboot Windows.
I just found this cool command when I used Chocolatey to install maven. Right at the end of the installation, Chocolatey prompt me to run the refreshenv command to have the environment variable change(s) take effect without re-opening the command prompt.
alvin@ALVINSIM-HP C:\Users\alvin\ &amp;gt; refreshenv Refreshing environment variables from registry for cmd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Design Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/my-design-portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 02:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/my-design-portfolio/</guid>
      <description>These are freelance works I have done alongside my career as a Software Developer/Engineer. They consists of websites (some are hybrid of HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Adobe Flash, whilst the others are just static HTML), magazine advertisements, and logos.
BioGalachrom URL: http://alvinsim.com/demo/biogalachrom/home/
A website built to provide information on a nutrient product called &amp;ldquo;GT&amp;amp;F&amp;rdquo;. This website is no longer online. The URL above is to an archived version.
Yong &amp;amp; Leonard Chartered Accountants URL: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symlink Me, Windows!</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/symlink-me-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 17:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/symlink-me-windows/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Windows has this feature called symbolic links since Windows Vista. But, I am guessing not many are aware of this feature, nor did I. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I had a need for it and tried searching if there were any 3rd party applications which provided this feature. And I found this How-To Geek article. Eventually, I found other articles on this subject.
What are symbolic links? Symbolic links are pointers referencing to another file or directory at a different location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Music With Sonic Pi</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/coding-music-with-sonic-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 13:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/coding-music-with-sonic-pi/</guid>
      <description>Sonic Pi Lately, I have been playing with Sonic Pi. In a nutshell, it is a music synthesizer. But instead of toggling knobs, switches, keys and what not, we write code. Ruby code to be exact.
Sonic Pi was created by Sam Aaron. A bit of history now, if you have not heard of him, he, together with Johnathan Graham, was Meta-eX. They performed live coding music. Besides that, they also did tech talks to promote coding and music to different groups of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip-of-the-day Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/tip-of-the-day-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 09:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/tip-of-the-day-tips/</guid>
      <description>We know it inside-out. Or do we? In our day-to-day life, we use a number of things or tools to get things done. Here, I want to touch mainly on software or applications, which we use almost everyday in our computer, smartphone, or tablet.
Source: Windows 95 Tips, Tricks and Tweaks
If anyone noticed, especially softwares on a desktop computer, there will always be a &amp;ldquo;Tip of the day&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Did you know?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagrams With PlantUML and Emacs</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/diagrams-with-plantuml-and-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 15:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/diagrams-with-plantuml-and-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Starting With Dia When I had to draw UML diagrams, the tool I first used was Dia - an open-sourced diagraming software. Dia is a great tool. I have not used Microsoft Visio before, so I cannot compare what short-comings it has compared to Visio.
The other tool I tried was yEd. I did not feel comfortable using it, and always went back to using Dia.
Couple of years ago, with a new job, I had to draw lots of sequence diagrams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember Me, Subversion</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/remember-me-svn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 16:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/remember-me-svn/</guid>
      <description>Every three months, my workplace&amp;rsquo;s network domain will prompt to change our password. And this tri-monthly exercise would affect all the other intranet sites and systems, namely Subversion (SVN). Now, this is not a major problem because the organisation uses single sign-on via LDAP or Active Directory i.e. you can access the other intanet sites or systems with the same User ID and password.
But recently, I noticed SVN doesn&amp;rsquo;t remember me, even when I clicked on the &amp;ldquo;Save authentication&amp;rdquo; check box at the TortoiseSVN&amp;rsquo;s authentication window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Now Licensed Under Creative Commons</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/creative-commons-licensed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 12:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/creative-commons-licensed/</guid>
      <description>Well, this website actually, including the blogs posts. Everything published here is now licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
In short, this means that you are allowed to (including for commercial works)
share any of the blog posts published here with anyone. use any of the blog posts to produce any form of works. There is just one request: Please provide a link back to the content and reference me as the author.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Tips - Move Window Between Multiple Monitor(s)</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/move-window-between-monitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 16:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/move-window-between-monitors/</guid>
      <description>Most of us now have additional external monitor in our workspace. Having more than one screen, which I find, makes one productive, especially when you need to reference data on another application. Using Alt Tab to switch between applications is not the best thing to do.
Prior to this, to move a window between monitors, I would use the mouse and drag it to the other screen. I have been doing this for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeBSD - Install Python 3 and Pip</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/freebsd-install-python-3-and-pip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 15:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/freebsd-install-python-3-and-pip/</guid>
      <description>I am starting a Python web project, and taking this oppotunity to learn django or flask. Development work will be done in my FreeBSD VirtualBox virtual machine.
Before I started, I checked if Python was already installed. And yes, it was already loaded with version 2.7.12.
[alvinsim@freebsd ~]$ which python /usr/local/bin/python [alvinsim@freebsd ~]$ python --version Python 2.7.12 [alvinsim@freebsd ~]$ But, I wanted to develop using Python 3. So, I searched if there was a port for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Vim To Emacs</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/from-vim-to-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 16:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/from-vim-to-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This is not a &amp;ldquo;Vim vs Emacs&amp;rdquo; type of blog post. I wrote this to share my thoughts of using both of them.
Vim Vi or vim (Vi IMproved) is a text editor. It is installed on almost all of the *nix systems. You can choose to use it with the GUI, or, use it in the terminal or command prompt.
I started using vim at around 2006/07. This was at one of my previous jobs where the servers were mainly *nix based systems - IBM AIX (ver 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate It!</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/automate-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 10:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/automate-it/</guid>
      <description>Image Credit - Eugen Stoll (Creative Commons License - CC BY-NC 2.0)
Machines are wonderful. They help us to be productive by doing the things we don&amp;rsquo;t want to do or can&amp;rsquo;t do, whilst we can focus on other important things.
Yes, I am LAZY! I write scripts or let services, like IFTTT (If-This-Then-That), to do things for me.
This is how I automate some of my daily routines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Do After I Install Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/things-i-do-after-i-install-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 17:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/things-i-do-after-i-install-windows/</guid>
      <description>1. Connect to a (trusted) network After the Windows installation completes successfully, I&amp;rsquo;d connect it to the Internet. This is so that I can update Windows with the latest security patches, and download the necessary applications.
2. Windows Update It is always important to always keep your Windows (or any other OS you use) up-to-date with the latest security patches and updates.
3. Check Windows Settings For Windows prior to Windows 10, I would configure Windows Update to notify only and not download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 15:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>I used to blog at my wordpress site. But now I have decided to merge both my website and blog since I already have my domain name and hosting. Unfortunately, this was something I had put off for a very long time.
What I will be blogging about? Hacks, things which inspires me and passionate about - coding/scripting, software development/engineering, tech, art, music, my kids. How-to articles especially for my own reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 16:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi. My name is Alvin Sim.
Throughout my career, which started in 2002, I have worn many hats.
At my first job, I started as a Graphic Designer, working for a small mobile content provider company.
After a year, I changed jobs and did Classic ASP and ASP.NET coding in VB. This was the start of my career as a Software Developer.
Moving forward in my career and because of project requirements, I picked-up Java and have been coding in Java ever since.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
