<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Alvin Sim</title>
    <link>http://localhost/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Alvin Sim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 12:58:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Now Licensed Under Creative Commons</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/creative-commons-licensed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 12:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/creative-commons-licensed/</guid>
      <description>Well, this website actually, including the blogs posts. Everything published here is now licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
In short, this means that you are allowed to (including for commercial works)
share any of the blog posts published here with anyone. use any of the blog posts to produce any form of works. There is just one request: Please provide a link back to the content and reference me as the author.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate It!</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/automate-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 10:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/automate-it/</guid>
      <description>Image Credit - Eugen Stoll (Creative Commons License - CC BY-NC 2.0)
Machines are wonderful. They help us to be productive by doing the things we don&amp;rsquo;t want to do or can&amp;rsquo;t do, whilst we can focus on other important things.
Yes, I am LAZY! I write scripts or let services, like IFTTT (If-This-Then-That), to do things for me.
This is how I automate some of my daily routines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 15:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>I used to blog at my wordpress site. But now I have decided to merge both my website and blog since I already have my domain name and hosting. Unfortunately, this was something I had put off for a very long time.
What I will be blogging about? Hacks, things which inspires me and passionate about - coding/scripting, software development/engineering, tech, art, music, my kids. How-to articles especially for my own reference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
