<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Others on Alvin Sim</title>
    <link>http://localhost/tags/others/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Others on Alvin Sim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 13:56:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost/tags/others/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Chocolatey Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/its-a-chocolatey-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 13:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/its-a-chocolatey-time/</guid>
      <description>Chocolatey is a software or package management on Windows, similar to the apt command on Debian or Debian-based distributions. It&amp;rsquo;d be great if Windows has something similar built-in. This does make managing software so much easier.
I have used Chocolatey for many years, since 2016 or earlier, and it is always one of the first things I install on a new Windows system.
One of the main advantages of using Chocolatey and because it is a command-line-interface (CLI) power tool, is installations and upgrading of software can be automated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Podcast Shows I Enjoy Listening To</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/2019-podcast-shows-i-enjoy-listening-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 12:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/2019-podcast-shows-i-enjoy-listening-to/</guid>
      <description>I listen to podcasts because it is one of the ways I can learn something new. There was a quote from someone, from whom I can&amp;rsquo;t remember, &amp;ldquo;Podcast is like a moving university&amp;rdquo;. I will always have something to listen to when I am doing my chores, commute, having my walks or exercise, etc.
Below is a list of the podcast shows I enjoy listening to currently and they are ordered in no particular order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Music With Sonic Pi</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/coding-music-with-sonic-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 13:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/coding-music-with-sonic-pi/</guid>
      <description>Sonic Pi Lately, I have been playing with Sonic Pi. In a nutshell, it is a music synthesizer. But instead of toggling knobs, switches, keys and what not, we write code. Ruby code to be exact.
Sonic Pi was created by Sam Aaron. A bit of history now, if you have not heard of him, he, together with Johnathan Graham, was Meta-eX. They performed live coding music. Besides that, they also did tech talks to promote coding and music to different groups of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip-of-the-day Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/tip-of-the-day-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 09:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/tip-of-the-day-tips/</guid>
      <description>We know it inside-out. Or do we? In our day-to-day life, we use a number of things or tools to get things done. Here, I want to touch mainly on software or applications, which we use almost everyday in our computer, smartphone, or tablet.
Source: Windows 95 Tips, Tricks and Tweaks
If anyone noticed, especially softwares on a desktop computer, there will always be a &amp;ldquo;Tip of the day&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Did you know?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Now Licensed Under Creative Commons</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/creative-commons-licensed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 12:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/creative-commons-licensed/</guid>
      <description>Well, this website actually, including the blogs posts. Everything published here is now licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
In short, this means that you are allowed to (including for commercial works)
share any of the blog posts published here with anyone. use any of the blog posts to produce any form of works. There is just one request: Please provide a link back to the content and reference me as the author.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>http://localhost/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 15:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>I used to blog at my wordpress site. But now I have decided to merge both my website and blog since I already have my domain name and hosting. Unfortunately, this was something I had put off for a very long time.
What I will be blogging about? Hacks, things which inspires me and passionate about - coding/scripting, software development/engineering, tech, art, music, my kids. How-to articles especially for my own reference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
